columbiasouthern.edu 2017-06-15

# Privacy Policy

Columbia Southern Education Group, Inc. (CSEG) and its subsidiaries including Columbia Southern University (CSU) and Waldorf University hold in high regard the privacy rights of our website visitors. We provide the following information describing what information we collect from site visitors and how that information is used to demonstrate our commitment to user privacy.

  1. **Non-Personally identifiable information.** CSU and Waldorf University collect a variety of information from website visitors. Some of this data is not personally identifiable and is collected automatically via the use of cookies and other standard web technology. Automatically-collected information might include: the operating system on your computer, the type of web browser you are using, your IP address, and the links you followed to enter and leave our site.
  2. **Personally identifiable information.** Personally identifiable information is collected only on a voluntary basis, at the option of the website user. For example, you may choose to provide your name, address or telephone number when submitting an information request on our website.
  3. **FERPA**. Personally identifiable information for enrolled students is protected by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ("FERPA") administered by the U.S. Department of Education. Additional information on FERPA is available here.
  4. **Use of information.** Non-personally identifiable information is used to help us improve our site by enabling us to discover and address the needs of our site visitors. This includes making our website accessible to the variety of Web browsers and operating systems used to access our site. Personal information collected through the site by means of your voluntary submission, such as your name, mailing address, e-mail address and other contact information, is used for the purpose of responding to your requests for information about CSU and Waldorf University products and services or to contact you about future products and services. Columbia Southern Education Group, Inc. does not share personal information with third parties, apart from release of "directory information" as described in the CSU FERPA policy or certain authorized vendors bound by confidentiality agreements with Columbia Southern Education Group who must utilize the information to perform necessary duties (such as credit card authorization, federal student aid processing and textbook ordering). "Directory information" disclosures include verifying enrollment for employment or credit application purposes.
  5. **Security of information.** Columbia Southern Education Group uses best efforts to protect security of personal information collected through its websites. Financial transactions submitted through the website are encrypted using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol.
  6. **User options regarding collection of information.** With regard to automatically collected information, it is standard practice for most Web sites to collect non-personally identifiable information about your web browser, operating system, IP address and browsing history (i.e. what pages on the CSU and Waldorf University websites viewed). Website users are unable to opt out of providing this non-personally identifiable information but please be assured that this information is collected only for Columbia Southern Education Group internal website development purposes to maintain optimal usability of the CSU and Waldorf University websites. Any other non-personal information collected through the use of cookies, may be opted out of by disabling or rejecting cookies for our site. For more information on cookies, including how you can delete or reject cookies, please refer to your web browser help file. Cookies help us to improve your web browsing experience with us. Disabling or rejecting cookies may impact your user experience as they are necessary to provide you with the correct geographically targeted information.
  7. **Requesting removal from CSU and Waldorf University marketing lists.** You may opt out of marketing solicitations at any time. To be removed from the marketing list, please contact the appropriate institution below: 
    * **Waldorf University (Online Programs)**  
PO Box 3269  
Orange Beach, AL 36561  
877-267-2157  
    * **Waldorf University (Residential Programs)**  
106 S. 6th Street  
Forest City, IA 50436  
800-292-1903  
    * **Columbia Southern University**  
Admissions Department  
P.O. Box 3110  
Orange Beach, AL 36561  
877-347-6050  
  8. **Limitation of liability.** The CSU and Waldorf University websites may contain links to third-party websites. Links to these websites are provided as a convenience only and should not be interpreted as an endorsement of the linked site, its operator or contents. We encourage our site visitors to review the privacy policies of each website they visit.
  9. **For more information.** For further information about this privacy policy, please contact us at: 

> Columbia Southern Education Group Inc.  
>  21982 University Lane  
>  Orange Beach, AL 36561
